number three asks which is the strongest
acid when we're talking about acid
strength what we need to understand is
that the strength of an acid is
proportional to the stability of the
conjugate base that sounds like a lot
but what we really mean here is that the
more stable the thing is that you get
the more readily the acid wants to
donate the proton meaning the stronger
the acid is so if we have HF HCL hbr hi
what are the conjugate bases of these
things what are we going to get if these
lose protons HF becomes F minus HCL
becomes CL minus hbr becomes BR minus
and hi becomes I minus so we get the
halide ions so now the question becomes
what is the relative stability of the
halide ions that are being produced now
what is the trend we want to look at
here what we understand is that the